<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>SCP Foundation Changchun Site</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://w163nana.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://w163nana.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2025-04-21T14:28:54.072Z</updated>
  <id>https://w163nana.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>ChenXinqi</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>python爬取YouTube视频大失败</title>
    <link href="https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/python%E7%88%AC%E5%8F%96YouTube%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E5%A4%A7%E5%A4%B1%E8%B4%A5/"/>
    <id>https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/python%E7%88%AC%E5%8F%96YouTube%E8%A7%86%E9%A2%91%E5%A4%A7%E5%A4%B1%E8%B4%A5/</id>
    <published>2025-04-21T14:02:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-04-21T14:28:54.072Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天和周涛组队做一个有关多克隆抗体的课堂展示，需要下载一个youtube视频。由于我之前学过一次，便信誓旦旦地把活儿接下来了。结果居然发现我忘记怎么写爬虫了。毕竟我不是专业学这个的，不能持续接触到编程的思维，所以记录就很重要了。我计划利用这个博客记录一些零碎的小收获。但是今天还没看专业教课书，就先不研究了。这学期四门专业课，加上两门课的补考，时间紧任务重，鸭梨山大啊……对了，最近我在玩《魔女的夜宴》。有压力的时候打开来看看美少女，感觉还挺不错的。今天偶然和潘宇浩单独唠了会嗑，感觉这个人还挺不错的诶。（和白容奇比起来，相处得要舒服多了）看来还是我们南方人的下数更合自己口味。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天和周涛组队做一个有关多克隆抗体的课堂展示，需要下载一个youtube视频。由于我之前学过一次，便信誓旦旦地把活儿接下来了。结果居然发现我忘记怎么写爬虫了。毕竟我不是专业学这个的，不能持续接触到编程的思维，所以记录就很重要了。我计划利用这个博客记录一些零碎的小收获。
但</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="python" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/categories/python/"/>
    
    
    <category term="python" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/python/"/>
    
    <category term="爬虫" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/%E7%88%AC%E8%99%AB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>《东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首》游戏策划</title>
    <link href="https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/%E3%80%8A%E4%B8%9C%E5%8C%97%E8%8A%AC%E8%BE%BE%E5%93%A5%E5%A4%A7%E6%88%98%E9%82%AA%E6%81%B6%E5%85%83%E9%A6%96%E3%80%8B%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F%E7%AD%96%E5%88%92/"/>
    <id>https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/%E3%80%8A%E4%B8%9C%E5%8C%97%E8%8A%AC%E8%BE%BE%E5%93%A5%E5%A4%A7%E6%88%98%E9%82%AA%E6%81%B6%E5%85%83%E9%A6%96%E3%80%8B%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F%E7%AD%96%E5%88%92/</id>
    <published>2025-04-13T12:26:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-04-13T12:28:16.109Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1id="东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首游戏策划方案">《东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首》游戏策划方案</h1><h2 id="一游戏概述">一、游戏概述</h2><ol type="1"><li><strong>游戏名称</strong>：《东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首》</li><li><strong>游戏类型</strong>：解谜类剧情游戏，融合电脑操作解谜、RPG回合制战斗、AVG 分支选择、战棋类战斗玩法</li><li><strong>游戏平台</strong>：PC</li><li><strong>游戏背景</strong>：在未来世界，科技高度发达，信息安全成为各国和各大组织争夺的关键。主角受雇于一个表面上维护世界信息安全，实则隐藏着巨大阴谋的神秘组织。在为组织工作的过程中，主角意外知晓了组织背后不可告人的秘密，从而陷入了一场危及生命的逃亡与反击之旅。</li></ol><h2 id="二游戏玩法">二、游戏玩法</h2><h3 id="一第一章组织内的电脑特工">（一）第一章：组织内的电脑特工</h3><ol type="1"><li><strong>剧情流程</strong>：  在未来的火星历 114年，人类迎来了和平的时代。此时，世界上仅存的若干政治实体结束了长期的对抗，携手共同开启了对外太空的开发征程。主人公芬达自幼父母双亡，无依无靠，自他有记忆起，便在一个名为PYRAMID的组织的安排下成长。这个组织是直属于星际开发联盟的高级别机构，而星际开发联盟是由地球上各个国家共同设立的，具备强大经济和武装能力的联盟，其主要目的是保障外太空资源能够实现和平、安全的开发。 在芬达的认知里，组织对外宣称自己是服务于联盟的特别行动分队，主要负责情报收集和精准打击任务。他作为组织内负责信息作战的工作人员，一直将那些野心勃勃的反动分子视为自己的敌人。 然而，一次偶然的机会改变了一切。有一天，芬达截获到了一条来自敌人高级别的加密信息。信息中提及了一些他看不懂的计划，强烈的好奇心驱使他开始顺藤摸瓜地进行调查。经过一段时间的深入探索，他逐渐了解到对方组织的真实目的——打破目前国际政府组织对太空探索的垄断（限飞政策）。由于芬达长期脱离社会，他并不知道外面的社会阶级分化已经达到了非常严重的程度。在外界，普通人根本没有能力拥有属于自己的飞船，只能到政府和少数个人拥有的飞船上从事极其危险的工作。而这个与组织对立的机构，实际上是由许多地下私飞组织联合建立的武装组织，他们的目的是进行自我防卫，以摆脱这种不公平的现状。 与此同时，芬达还在调查过程中发现了星际开发联盟对其反对者施加触目惊心迫害的证据。他深知这些证据一旦曝光，将会引起轩然大波。但他并未声张，而是继续秘密调查。 随着调查的深入，芬达开始参与到组织的战场资源调度工作中。他通过截获的情报和先进的数据分析系统，为组织提供战场形势的评估，并负责调度战斗力和补给等资源。在这个过程中，他逐渐发现组织的行动往往是为了维护少数人的利益，而那些被视为“敌人” 的地下私飞组织，实际上是为了争取普通人的生存权利而战。 内心的良知开始觉醒，芬达在资源调度时开始有意无意地偏袒敌方组织。比如，当他得知组织计划对地下私飞组织的某个据点发动攻击时，他会故意延迟战斗力的派遣，或者减少补给的供应。他会通过修改情报数据，让组织误以为敌方据点的防御力量比实际更强，从而放弃攻击计划。又或者在分配补给物资时，他会巧妙地让一些关键物资无法按时送达组织的前线部队，而在某些情况下，甚至会制造一些意外，让部分补给物资“误送” 到敌方组织的控制区域。 然而，纸终究包不住火。某天，那些被芬达一直隐藏的证据意外泄露了。组织的网络安全团队迅速展开调查，他们通过复杂的网络流量分析技术，追踪到了芬达在调查过程中留下的蛛丝马迹。尽管芬达已经非常小心地隐藏自己的行为，但组织的技术人员还是通过对他访问敏感信息的时间、频率以及与外部网络的异常连接等细节进行分析，错误地将矛头指向了他，认定是他泄露了这些证据。 当组织的武装人员即将破门而入逮捕他时，芬达意识到自己的生命受到了严重威胁，于是他果断地开始了逃亡之旅，游戏剧情也由此进入第二部分。</li><li><strong>工作环境</strong>：玩家身处组织的机密情报中心，这里摆满了各种先进的电脑设备和监控屏幕。玩家通过操作电脑来完成组织分配的任务。</li><li><strong>操作功能解锁</strong><ul><li><strong>初期</strong>：骇入、上报。</li><li><strong>后期</strong>：指挥。</li></ul></li><li><strong>数值系统</strong>：<ul><li><strong>初期</strong>：骇入获取情报点数，上报将其转换成功劳点数，功劳点数用于在每日结束时购买权限和技能。</li><li><strong>后期</strong>：解锁指挥权限后，开放指挥技能的学习。指挥需要权力点数，权力点数由功劳点数换汇得来。指挥的战斗胜利亦可获得功劳点数。</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id="二第二章逃亡与调查">（二）第二章：逃亡与调查</h3><ol type="1"><li><strong>逃亡背景</strong>：主角在真女主的接应下逃亡到反对组织的总部。</li><li><strong>剧情流程</strong>：<ol type="1"><li>泉此方结局：<ol type="1"><li>职位：情报员</li><li>可用装备：S码的所有装备、重量低于1.5kg的进展或远程武器。</li><li>技能：获取情报</li><li>剧情任务：前往政府军前哨窃取情报。</li><li>好感度增加方法：给漫画、手办，陪打游戏。</li><li>好结局前提：获取情报“进攻方位”、好感度满。</li><li>坏结局触发条件：选择不符合原作角色性格的分支。</li></ol></li><li>牧濑红莉栖结局：<ol type="1"><li>职位：研发员</li><li>可用装备：远程武器，轻、中甲。</li><li>技能：动作如潮</li><li>剧情任务：野外收集装备零件。</li><li>好感度增加方法：建设未来机械研究所。</li><li>好结局前提：建成未来机械研究所，搜集到足够的零件以制作纳豆沙拉炮。</li><li>坏结局触发条件：选择不符合原作角色性格的分支。</li></ol></li><li>黑羽早雪结局：<ol type="1"><li>职位：战士</li><li>装备：Black Lotus</li><li>技能：鼓舞（蓄力）</li><li>剧情任务：抵御一次进攻</li><li>好感度增加方法：一开始就是满的</li><li>好结局前提：任务完成、好感度满、已解锁另2个结局</li><li>坏结局触发条件：选择不符合原作角色性格的分支。</li></ol></li><li>真结局：解锁前3个结局后，玩家在此方和红莉栖的帮助下骇入联盟系统，得知PYRAMID的主管“元首”正在秘密采集鬼畜矿石。他希望利用鬼畜之力完成人类到原神的补完计划。芬达下意识地产生了阻止他的想法，辞别三女主，踏上第三章的征途。他的决心感染了基地的众人，鬼畜战斗组的成员更是坚决的与我们的主角一起出征了。</li></ol></li><li><strong>RPG 回合制战斗</strong></li><li><strong>分支选择 AVG</strong></li></ol><h3 id="三第三章大决战">（三）第三章：大决战</h3><ol type="1"><li><strong>游戏流程</strong>：<ul><li><strong>第一关</strong>：火星前哨。BOSS：红红。</li><li><strong>第二关</strong>：月球堡垒。BOSS：佟Dark为。</li><li><strong>第三关</strong>：地球总部。BOSS：元首。</li></ul></li><li><strong>战棋类战斗</strong><ul><li><strong>战场设定</strong>：战斗在棋盘式的地图上进行，每个格子代表一个行动区域。玩家操控自己的部下在棋盘上移动、攻击敌人。</li><li><strong>单位类型</strong>：有近战、远程、魔法等不同类型的部下，每个单位有不同的移动范围、攻击范围和技能。</li></ul></li><li><strong>剧情推进与分支选择</strong><ul><li><strong>选择</strong>：只有结局一个分支选择：是阻止补完计划还是不阻止。</li></ul></li></ol><h2 id="三角色系统">三、角色系统</h2><ol type="1"><li><strong>主角</strong>：拥有独特的电脑操作技能和智慧，在不同阶段有不同的能力表现。在第一阶段是组织的优秀特工，第二阶段成为逃亡者和调查员，第三阶段成为势力领袖。</li><li><strong>伙伴角色</strong><ul><li><strong>第二阶段伙伴</strong>：具有RPG角色的等级机制，可以刷级。</li><li><strong>第三阶段部下</strong>：具有RPG角色的等级机制，可以刷级。同时也有招募机制，每次携带的队友有数量限制。</li></ul></li></ol><h2 id="四游戏画面与音效">四、游戏画面与音效</h2><ol type="1"><li><strong>画面风格</strong>：生草的灵魂手绘风 + 鬼畜大头贴</li><li><strong>音效设计</strong>：第一阶段有电脑操作的音效；第二阶段有Galgame背景音乐、战斗音乐、战斗音效等；第三阶段有战棋移动和攻击的音效、战斗音乐。</li></ol><h2 id="五游戏流程">五、游戏流程</h2><ol type="1"><li><strong>第一阶段剧情推进</strong></li><li><strong>第二阶段多周目体验</strong></li><li><strong>第三阶段决战</strong></li></ol><h2 id="六开发计划">六、开发计划</h2><ul><li>已新建文件夹</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1
id=&quot;东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首游戏策划方案&quot;&gt;《东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首》游戏策划方案&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;一游戏概述&quot;&gt;一、游戏概述&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;游戏名称&lt;/strong&gt;：《东北芬达哥大战邪恶元首》&lt;/li</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="开发" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/categories/%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91/"/>
    
    
    <category term="游戏" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F/"/>
    
    <category term="开发" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91/"/>
    
    <category term="鬼畜" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/%E9%AC%BC%E7%95%9C/"/>
    
    <category term="Galgame" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Galgame/"/>
    
    <category term="AVG" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/AVG/"/>
    
    <category term="战棋" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/%E6%88%98%E6%A3%8B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Nano Ultrasound Contrast Agent for Synergistic Chemo-photothermal Therapy and Enhanced Immunotherapy Against Liver Cancer and Metastasis</title>
    <link href="https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/Nano-Ultrasound-Contrast-Agent-for-Synergistic-Chemo-photothermal-Therapy-and-Enhanced-Immunotherapy-Against-Liver-Cancer-and-Metastasis/"/>
    <id>https://w163nana.github.io/wiki/Nano-Ultrasound-Contrast-Agent-for-Synergistic-Chemo-photothermal-Therapy-and-Enhanced-Immunotherapy-Against-Liver-Cancer-and-Metastasis/</id>
    <published>2025-04-12T07:09:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-04-12T07:19:47.575Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2><p>Liver cancer is a major global health concern, with approximately 1million new patients diagnosed each year. [cite: 502, 63, 64] Asignificant number of these patients are diagnosed at an advanced stage,making them ineligible for surgical treatments. [cite: 502, 63, 64] Insuch cases, traditional treatment methods like thermal ablation,chemotherapy, and immunotherapy often yield unsatisfactory results dueto the complexity and heterogeneity of the tumor. [cite: 503, 65] Thepropensity of liver cancer to metastasize adds another layer ofdifficulty to treatment and severely impacts patient prognosis. [cite:504, 66] Consequently, there’s a critical need for research focused ondeveloping effective combination therapies that can enhance treatmentefficacy and reduce metastasis. [cite: 505, 67]</p><p>Combination therapy, which strategically employs multiple treatmentmodalities, has emerged as a promising approach to improve outcomes.[cite: 493, 54] By targeting various pathways and modulating the tumor’simmune microenvironment, combination therapy can more effectivelydisrupt cancer progression. [cite: 493, 54] Among the innovative toolsbeing explored for liver cancer treatment, nanodrug delivery systemshold significant promise. [cite: 494, 55] These systems offer thepotential for targeted drug delivery, reduced toxicity, and enhancedtherapeutic efficacy. [cite: 494, 55]</p><p>This study introduces a novel nano ultrasound contrast agent,abbreviated as ATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD, designed to integrate diagnosis andtreatment for efficient ultrasound imaging and liver cancer therapy.[cite: 495, 56]</p><p>The core components of this system are:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Arsenic trioxide (ATO):</strong> A therapeutic agentknown to induce ferroptosis, a distinct form of programmed cell death,in tumor cells. [cite: 495, 56, 512, 74]</p></li><li><p><strong>Perfluorohexane (PFH):</strong> A substance used toenhance the ultrasound echo signal. [cite: 495, 56, 528, 94]</p></li><li><p><strong>Gold nanoparticles (AuNPs):</strong> Act as a carrier forATO and PFH and facilitate photothermal therapy (PTT). [cite: 495, 56,508, 70]</p></li><li><p><strong>cRGD peptide:</strong> A targeting ligand that enhancesthe delivery of the nano-agent to liver cancer cells. [cite: 495, 56,529, 95]</p></li></ul><p>The research demonstrates that this nanodrug delivery system promotesthe release of tumor-associated antigens (TAAs) through ATO-inducedferroptosis and photothermal-induced immunogenic cell death. [cite: 496,57] This process enhances the synergistic effects of ATO andphotothermal therapy in human Huh7 and mouse Hepa1-6 cells. [cite: 496,57]</p><p>A key finding of the study is the system’s ability to activate theantitumor immune response and promote macrophage M1 polarization withinthe tumor microenvironment. [cite: 497, 58] Notably, these beneficialeffects were observed with low side effects in both subcutaneous andorthotopic liver cancer models. [cite: 497, 58]</p><p>Furthermore, the research reveals that combining the nanodrugdelivery system with anti-programmed death-ligand 1 (PD-L1)immunotherapy inhibits tumor metastasis and establishes long-termimmunological memory in orthotopic liver cancer. [cite: 498, 59] Thiscombination not only enhances antitumor therapy and suppresses lungmetastasis but also enables visual assessment of therapeutic efficacy.[cite: 499, 60] These capabilities highlight the significant potentialof this nano-agent for clinical applications in treating liver cancer.[cite: 499, 60]</p><h2 id="detailed-discussion-of-key-components-and-mechanisms">DetailedDiscussion of Key Components and Mechanisms</h2><h3 id="arsenic-trioxide-ato-and-ferroptosis">Arsenic Trioxide (ATO) andFerroptosis</h3><p>Arsenic trioxide (ATO) has shown considerable clinical benefits inthe palliative treatment of unresectable primary liver cancer. [cite:518, 83] However, its clinical application is limited by high systemictoxicity, rapid renal elimination of ATO, and low delivery efficiency toliver cancer cells, which greatly reduce the therapeutic efficacy andlead to severe systemic toxicity. [cite: 519, 84, 520, 85, 86]</p><p>To address these limitations, nanotechnology-based nanodrug deliverysystems offer a promising solution. [cite: 521, 87] These systems cansignificantly improve the efficacy of ATO, reduce its toxicity, andachieve targeted drug delivery in liver cancer. [cite: 521, 87] SinceATO has a strong affinity for sulfhydryl groups (SH) in proteins, it cantheoretically inactivate a variety of enzymes containing SH, such asglutathione (GSH). [cite: 521, 87]</p><p>Glutathione (GSH) could assist glutathione peroxidase 4 (GPX4) inreducing toxic lipid peroxides (LPOs) to nontoxic hydroxy compound (LOH)to prevent LPO-mediated damage to cell membrane structure and function.[cite: 522, 88] The depletion of GSH could result in the inhibition ofGPX4 activity and a corresponding increase in intracellular LPO levels,ultimately leading to ferroptosis. [cite: 522, 88] Therefore, ATO mayinduce ferroptosis through GSH depletion and GPX4 inactivation. [cite:522, 88] Moreover, the ferroptosis-induced release of TAAs from dyingcancer cells could further enhance the immune response. [cite: 522,88]</p><h3id="photothermal-therapy-ptt-and-gold-nanoparticles-aunps">PhotothermalTherapy (PTT) and Gold Nanoparticles (AuNPs)</h3><p>Photothermal therapy (PTT) is an anticancer strategy that offersprecise targeting of tumors with minimal damage to surrounding healthytissues. [cite: 506, 68, 507, 69] Gold nanoparticles (AuNPs) arewell-suited for PTT applications due to their good biocompatibility andexcellent optical properties. [cite: 508, 70]</p><p>When AuNPs are exposed to near-infrared (NIR) light, they efficientlyabsorb the light energy and convert it into heat. [cite: 509, 71] Thisphotothermal effect can damage tumor tissues or release therapeuticmolecules, such as tumor-associated antigens (TAAs). [cite: 509, 71,516, 80] However, the therapeutic effect of AuNPs alone may be limited.[cite: 516, 80, 517, 81] The synergistic effect of combined chemo-PTTmay be a promising strategy for improving PTT efficacy. [cite: 517, 81,506, 68]</p><h3id="ultrasound-targeted-microbubble-destruction-utmd">Ultrasound-TargetedMicrobubble Destruction (UTMD)</h3><p>Ultrasound-targeted microbubble destruction (UTMD) can be exploitedto change the structures of cells to facilitate the targeted release ofnanodrugs into tumor cells, which could improve the efficacy of tumortreatment and prevent the systemic toxicity of antitumor drugs. [cite:525, 91] The nanoparticles (NPs) accumulate in tumor tissues through theenhanced permeability and retention effect (EPR) and targeting effect.[cite: 526, 92] Then, UTMD can increase the permeability of the cellmembrane through the cavitation effect so that the drugs loaded in NPsare more easily released and taken up. [cite: 527, 93] Moreover, NPs canalso load imaging agents for visualizing therapy, such asperfluorohexane (PFH). [cite: 528, 94]</p><h3 id="the-role-of-crgd-peptide">The Role of cRGD Peptide</h3><p>In this study, the nanodrug delivery system is conjugated with thecyclic arginylglycylaspartic acid peptide (cRGD). [cite: 529, 95, 530,96] Since ανβ3 integrin-specific ligands are overexpressed in livercancer and neovascularization cells, a cyclic arginylglycylaspartic acidpeptide (cRGD) can be bound to AuNPs via gold-sulfur bonds for targetedliver cancer therapy. [cite: 530, 96, 531, 97, 532, 98]</p><h3 id="perfluorohexane-pfh-and-ultrasound-imaging">Perfluorohexane(PFH) and Ultrasound Imaging</h3><p>Perfluorohexane (PFH) is a stable, safe, and nontoxic liquid that canundergo a phase transition and enhance the ultrasound echo signal underultrasonic stimulation and photothermal effects. [cite: 528, 94, 529,95, 535, 100] This property makes it valuable for ultrasound imaging,allowing for the visualization of the nano-agent’s distribution andtherapeutic effects. [cite: 535, 100, 536, 101]</p><h2 id="mechanism-of-action-of-the-nano-agent">Mechanism of Action ofthe Nano-Agent</h2><p>The nano ultrasound contrast agent, ATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD, functionsthrough a multifaceted mechanism:</p><ol type="1"><li><p><strong>Induction of Ferroptosis:</strong> ATO inducesferroptosis in tumor cells through GSH depletion and increased GPX4.[cite: 512, 74] The increased ROS can also directly kill tumor cells,thereby enhancing the synergistic effect. [cite: 512, 74, 513, 75, 513,76, 514, 77]</p></li><li><p><strong>Photothermal Effect:</strong> AuNPs generate heat underNIR laser irradiation, contributing to tumor cell death. [cite: 506, 68,507, 69, 508, 70, 509, 71]</p></li><li><p><strong>Immune Modulation:</strong> Ferroptosis and photothermaleffects promote the maturation of dendritic cells (DCs) and macrophageM1 polarization in the tumor microenvironment (TME). [cite: 514, 78]This activation of the immune system triggers an adaptive T-cellresponse, leading to the generation of cytotoxic T lymphocytes that canattack tumor cells. [cite: 514, 78]</p></li><li><p><strong>Enhanced Immunotherapy:</strong> The anti-PD-L1 mAbfurther promotes the anti-tumor effect of cytotoxic T lymphocytes byblocking the PD-1/PD-L1 axis, which enables synergistic treatment oforthotopic liver cancer, enhances the immune response, and reduces lungmetastasis. [cite: 515, 79]</p></li></ol><p>In essence, this nanodrug delivery system could realize visualimaging, enable synergistic treatment of liver cancer, enhance theimmune response and influence the phenotypes of macrophages in TME,thereby achieving enhanced liver tumor therapy, reducing metastasis, andenabling visual assessment of therapeutic efficacy. [cite: 536, 101,537, 102]</p><h2 id="synthesis-and-characterization-of-the-nano-agent">Synthesis andCharacterization of the Nano-Agent</h2><p>The ATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD nano-agent is synthesized using afilming-rehydration method with minor modifications to establishedprotocols. [cite: 538, 103, 539, 104]</p><ul><li><p><strong>Lipid Membranes:</strong> <spanclass="math-inline">DSPE-PEG_{2K}</span> , a biocompatible,biodegradable, and amphiphilic material, is used as a backbone toconstruct aptamer-functionalized core-shell nanoparticles. [cite: 539,104, 540, 105, 541, 106] <spanclass="math-inline">DSPE-PEG_{2k}</span>-SI, DOTAP, DPPC, andcholesterol formed lipid membranes to load ATO and PFH, and tosynthesize ATO/PFH NPs. [cite: 541, 106, 542, 107]</p></li><li><p><strong>Gold Nanoshells:</strong> AuNPs were deposited onto thesurface of liposomes via reduction of chloroauric acid <spanclass="math-inline">(HAuCl_{4})</span> following a previously reportedmethod. [cite: 542, 107, 533, 98, 534, 99, 543, 108] Then, RGD-SH bindsto the gold shell through SH bonds. [cite: 542, 107, 533, 98, 534, 99,543, 108]</p></li><li><p><strong>cRGD Conjugation:</strong> cRGD-SH is then bound to thegold shell via SH bonds to achieve targeted delivery. [cite: 542, 107,533, 98, 534, 99, 543, 108]</p></li></ul><p>The successful synthesis of the nano-agent is confirmed throughvarious characterization techniques:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM):</strong> TEMconfirmed the deposition of AuNPs on the liposome surface. [cite: 543,108, 544, 109]</p></li><li><p><strong>Hydrodynamic Diameter and Zeta Potential:</strong> Thehydrodynamic diameter was 121 ± 5 nm, and the Zeta potential was 10.47 ±1.20 mV in aqueous solution. [cite: 544, 109, 545, 110, 546,111]</p></li><li><p><strong>Size Distribution:</strong> The size range of the ATO/PFHNPs@Au-cRGD was ≈100-150 nm. [cite: 545, 110, 546, 111]</p></li><li><p><strong>Stability Analysis:</strong> After storage at 4, 25, and37°C in phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) and serum (5%, pH 7.4) for 7days, there was no obvious change in particle size and Zeta potential,indicating good stability of the synthesized nanoparticles. [cite: 546,111, 547, 112]</p></li><li><p><strong>UV-Vis Spectra:</strong> UV-vis spectra showed thatATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD had a characteristic plasmonic coupling (between theAuNPs) absorption peak at 760 nm, while no resonance peak at thenear-infrared wavelengths was detected in non-coated liposomes. [cite:547, 112, 548, 113, 549, 114]</p></li><li><p><strong>Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy (EDS):</strong> EDSanalysis further confirms the formation of a gold shell surrounding theliposome core. [cite: 547, 112, 548, 113, 549, 114]</p></li></ul><h2 id="in-vitro-drug-release-and-ultrasound-imaging">In Vitro DrugRelease and Ultrasound Imaging</h2><p>The study also investigates the controlled release ability of ATOfrom the nanodrug delivery system and its ultrasound imagingcapabilities. [cite: 549, 115, 550, 116]</p><ul><li><p><strong>Drug Release:</strong> The drug release characteristicsof ATO were detected at pH 7.4 and 6.5 (pH 6.5 was used to simulate theslightly acidic TME). [cite: 549, 115, 550, 116, 551, 117, 552, 118]Compared to the fast release of free ATO (≈92% in 24 h), ATO NPs-cRGDshowed significant sustained release. [cite: 551, 117, 552, 118] ATO canbe effectively released with the aid of an ultrasound therapeuticapparatus and low acidity TME (PH 6.5). [cite: 553, 120, 554, 121] Theacoustic cavitation effect generated by UTMD is a process of vibration,expansion, contraction, and rupture of microbubbles, which lead to thedestruction of the nanocarrier and the release of the drug encapsulatedin the nanoparticles, thus promoting the selective release at the tumorsite. [cite: 555, 122]</p></li><li><p><strong>Ultrasound Imaging:</strong> In vivo and in vitro imagingexperiments were carried out with saline as a negative control andSonoVue contrast agent as a positive control to evaluate the ultrasoundimaging ability of ATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD. [cite: 556, 123, 557, 124, 558,125] The contrast-enhanced images of SonoVue and ATO/PFH NPs@Au-CRGDwere significantly enhanced in vitro after ultrasound exposure, andsimilar results were detected in in vivo imaging. [cite: 556, 123, 557,124, 558, 125] Compared to commercial ultrasound contrast agents, theATO/PFH NPS@Au-cRGD exhibited similar ultrasound imaging effects intumors, clearly showing contrast enhancement in contrast mode, whichcould assess the dynamic blood perfusion of tumors visually, therebyrealizing precise molecular imaging during treatment. [cite: 560,127]</p></li><li><p><strong>Photothermal Properties:</strong> The photothermalproperties of the ATO/PFH NPs@Au-cRGD were investigated using a 760 nmlaser to irradiate PBS, AuNPs, ATO, and ATO NPs@Au-cRGD. [cite: 561,128, 562, 129] After 4 min of irradiation, the maximum temperatures ofthe AuNPs and ATO NPs@Au-cRGD were 54.2 ± 0.6°C and 48.7 ± 0.7°C,respectively.</p></li></ul><h2 id="references">References</h2><blockquote><ul><li><ahref="https://advanced.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/advs.202300878">QiuY, Wu Z, Chen Y, Liao J, Zhang Q, Wang Q, Duan Y, Gong K, Chen S, WangL, Fan P, Duan Y, Wang W, Dong Y. Nano Ultrasound Contrast Agent forSynergistic Chemo-photothermal Therapy and Enhanced ImmunotherapyAgainst Liver Cancer and Metastasis. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2023Jul;10(21):e2300878. doi: 10.1002/advs.202300878. Epub 2023 May 10.PMID: 37162268; PMCID: PMC10375134.</a></li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liver cancer is a major global health concern, with approximately 1
million new patients diagno</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Medical Research" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/categories/Medical-Research/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Liver Cancer" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Liver-Cancer/"/>
    
    <category term="Arsenic Trioxide (ATO)" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Arsenic-Trioxide-ATO/"/>
    
    <category term="Photothermal Therapy (PTT)" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Photothermal-Therapy-PTT/"/>
    
    <category term="Ferroptosis" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Ferroptosis/"/>
    
    <category term="Immunogenic Cell Death" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Immunogenic-Cell-Death/"/>
    
    <category term="PD-L1 Inhibito" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/PD-L1-Inhibito/"/>
    
    <category term="Ultrasound Contrast Agent" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/Ultrasound-Contrast-Agent/"/>
    
    <category term="cRGD Peptide" scheme="https://w163nana.github.io/tags/cRGD-Peptide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
